<resources>
    <string name="app_name">TreeApp</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="tfe_ic_app_name" translation_description="Image Classification demo app [CHAR_LIMIT=40]">TFL Classify</string>
    <string name="tfe_ic_camera_error" translation_description="Error regarding camera support[CHAR_LIMIT=40]">This device doesn\'t support Camera2 API.</string>
    <string name="tfe_ic_gpu_quant_error" translation_description="Error regarding GPU support for Quant models[CHAR_LIMIT=60]">GPU does not yet supported quantized models.</string>
    <string name="tfe_ic_model" translatable="false">Model:</string>
    <string-array name="tfe_ic_models" translatable="false">
        <item>Quantized_EfficientNet</item>
        <item>Float_EfficientNet</item>
        <item>Quantized_MobileNet</item>
        <item>Float_MobileNet</item>
        <item>Leaf</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="tfe_ic_device" translatable="false">Device:</string>
    <string-array name="tfe_ic_devices" translatable="false">
        <item>CPU</item>
        <item>GPU</item>
        <item>NNAPI</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="what_is_dendrology">Dendrology actually means "the study of trees." In common usage it has come to mean
the taxonomy of woody plants (Harlow and others 1979), which is the systematic
classification, naming, and identification of trees based on natural attributes and
relationships. The study of dendrology also includes knowledge about characteristics of
trees and their geographical range.</string>

    <string name="dendrology_in_urban_foresty">Learning how to identify trees takes time and experience, but once familiar with how to
do it, it is a valuable skill for urban foresters. Some activities in which knowing about
dendrology will be most useful are noted in table</string>

    <string name="classification_of_trees">Since ancient times, humans have attempted to classify plants. Today, there is no single
method of classifying plants because of the complexity of relationships among plants.
The U.S. and other countries prefer a system developed by German taxonomists Adolf
Engler and Karl Pramtl. This plant classification system provides a systematic way to
identify trees based on genetic relationships. It also facilitates the communication
between people when they are discussing specific plants. Two principles of this system
are important in understanding how plants are categorized:
<br />· The reproductive organs (flowers and fruit) are the basis of the classification
system. Other important characteristics are leaves and wood anatomy. Trees can
be classified as closely related when they have similar fruits even though they
have different leaves and buds..
<br />· The characteristics of a tree in its natural habitat influence its classification.</string>

    <string name="classification_definitions">Using the classification system requires knowing the terminology and definitions used in
dendrology. The classifications in table 2 divide trees into increasingly smaller groups;
each one is given a Latin name. This method of naming natural things is common in
science. Knowing the family name helps to understand relationships among trees. The
genus and species names are the most important ones to know because a tree’s scientific
name is made up of these two names, such as Magnolia grandiflora (southern magnolia).
Table 3 shows an example of the classification structure for the loblolly pine, a
gymnosperm, and the Southern red oak, an angiosperm. The definitions in table 4 are
often used to describe trees found in urban areas. </string>
    <string name="order_description">Trees are further classified into orders according to certain other characteristics of seed reproduction. Angiosperms are divided into two major groups, monocotyledons and dicotyledons, based in part on the number of primary leaves (one or two) present in the seed plant. The Sabal palmetto is an example of a monocotyledon. Most trees are dicotyledons, such as members of the walnut or oak families.</string>
    <string name="class_definition">Trees are then divided into two classes, Gymnosperms and Angiosperms, by the method they use to develop the seeds used for reproduction. Gymnosperms, such as conifers, produce an open seed on a structure such as a cone. Angiosperms are flowering trees that have seeds enclosed in an ovary.</string>
    <string name="division_definition">This is the first category of the plant kingdom and is based on the plant’s means of reproduction. Trees, in the Spermatophyte division, reproduce through seeds.</string>
    <string name="kingdom_definition">All living things are classified into kingdoms (e.g. plants and animals). Trees are in the plant kingdom</string>
    <string name="family_description">A group of closely related trees, usually including one or more genera (plural of genus) make up a family. The rose family, Rosaceae, is a family in the dicot group, and includes cherry, apple, and pear trees.</string>
    <string name="genus_description">A collection of closely related species is a genus. The species usually are structurally similar or have common ancestry. Examples are the cherry and plum trees that are a genus, Prunus, of the rose family</string>
    <string name="species_definition">A collection of individuals with characteristics so similar that they suggest common parentage, a species is a tree distinct and unlike others. The black cherry, Prunus serotina, is a species of the genus Prunus. Species is the basic, and probably most important (Dirr 1990) unit of taxonomy or classification of a tree.</string>
    <string name="hybrid_definition">A tree produced by crossing two different species is considered a hybrid. Hybridization has been used to create new variations of a species for urban areas. An example is the Cornus.kousa x florida.celestial, a hybrid of the Kousa dogwood and the flowering dogwood that was developed for greater resistance to disease</string>
    <string name="veriety_definition">Within a species, a tree that has distinctive but minor differences from other trees of the same species is a variety. These differences are inheritable and can be reproduced from seed (Dirr 1990). A variety that is significantly different from the standard species is often the beginning of a new species. Variations in the color of the leaves or flowers or a difference in the fruit will distinguish one variety of a tree from others in the species.</string>
    <string name="cultivar_definition">Trees that have been cultivated to produce specific, distinguishing characteristics are cultivars. These specimens retain the features created in the development of the cultivar, but they usually can only be reproduced by grafting to maintain the characteristics. This method of reproduction distinguishes it from a variety, although the term cultivar and variety are often used interchangeably (Dirr 1990).</string>
    <string name="clone_definition">A population of trees that develops asexually from a single tree is a clone. Sassafras and sweetgum are trees that reproduce as clones.</string>
    <string name="natives_definition">Trees that are indigenous to a particular region or environment are considered to be native. This usually suggests that the species originated in the region and has a certain compatibility with it. A native tree, however, may not be compatible in urban locations in that region because of modifications to the habitat, including soil, water, and nutrient cycles.</string>
    <string name="exotics_definition">Trees that are not native to the area in which they grow are considered to be exotics. Exotics may be resistant to local insect and disease problems, but may also bring in unexpected and undesirable insect and diseases. They may also become invasive. Exotics become naturalized when they grow and reproduce in an area.</string>
    <string name="naming_trees">Naming trees with Latin names is the second component of tree taxonomy. Each species has a scientific Latin name that is used universally. However, every tree also has one or more common names by which it is known in various parts of its range.</string>
    <string name="scientific_name">A system of standardized Latin names for plants was developed in the 18th century and is now used throughout the world as a universal system for naming trees. The complete scientific name for a tree consists of three parts: <br />· Genus; for the loblolly pine it is Pinus <br />· Species; for the loblolly pine it is Pinus taeda <br />· The full or abbreviated name of the person or persons who originally described the species; the full name of the loblolly pine is Pinus taeda L (L. is the initial for Linnaeus, the Swedish botanist of the 18th century).</string>
    <string name="common_name">The common names of trees often reflect their major characteristics, such as the red maple. Names, however, may originate from other sources, such as the location where the trees grow naturally. Examples are swamp white oak and river birch, trees that grow in low-lying or riparian areas with moist soils. Some of the sources of common tree names are: <br />· Habitat - swamp white oak, river birch <br />· Distinctive feature - weeping willow, bigleaf maple <br />· Locality or region - southern red oak, southern magnolia <br />· Use - sugar maple, paper mulberry <br />· In commemoration - Douglas fir, Englemann spruce <br />· Adaptations from other languages - frijolito, hickory <br />Using common names of trees often leads to confusion when talking with other people. Two trees, like two humans, may share the same common name while actually being quite dissimilar. Trees may also have multiple names. For example, loblolly pine is known in various parts of its range by 25 other names, including juice pine and bull pine. The American Joint Committee on Horticultural Nomenclature has attempted to adopt one common name for each species (Harlow and others 1979).</string>
    <string name="tree_identification">The identification of trees is the third aspect of tree taxonomy or classification. Trees are classified into groups primarily by their fruits and flowers, but the leaves and twigs are usually more accessible for identification. Tree identification in urban locations requires knowing many trees because of the numerous exotics that have been introduced from around the country and the world. The most important features to look for in identifying a tree are: <br />· leaves <br />· twigs and stems <br />· bark <br />· flowers <br />· fruit and seeds <br />· cones <br />Trees are identified by several different methods. Parts of a tree may be compared to illustrations in a manual, although this can be time consuming. A better way is to use keys specifically designed to aid in identifying trees.</string>
    <string name="keys_definition">Keys are tools that lead the user through the steps of identification based on the features of the tree. The key often focuses on the fruit or flower since this is the primary means for classifying trees. However, keys have also been developed for other features such as leaves, stems, buds and bark. <br />Using a key involves making choices at each step in the outline provided. It begins with general, easily observable features and works through to increasingly detailed traits. To do this successfully requires practice, experience, patience and familiarity with the scientific terminology used. A key is intended only to help in tree identification, and should not be the only means used in doing the job (Dirr 1990).</string>
    <string name="leaves_identification_definition">One way to identify a tree is by its leaves. Leaves have many distinguishing characteristics and these characteristics can be used for identification. Each of these features will be defined and illustrated in this unit: <br />· Part <br />· Type <br />· Shape <br />· Arrangement on the stem <br />· Venation <br />· Shape of apex and base <br />· Margin <br />· Surface</string>
    <string name="leaf_parts">Knowing the parts of a leaf will help with tree identification. <br />· The lamina is the blade or broad part of the leaf. <br />· The leaf is attached to the twig with a supporting stalk called a petiole. It may be either short or long, grow in a variety of different shapes, and may not exist in some trees. Some petioles enclose next season’s bud in the base. When the leaf is attached directly to the twig, rather than to the petiole, it is said to be sessile. <br />· Stipules are a pair of small, scaly or leaf-like organs that may be attached to the twig on either side of the petiole. Some stipules will leave scars that are visible on the twig in the winter. Plants that have stipules are called stipulate, while those without them are called estipulate.</string>
    <string name="leaf_types_1">Determining the type of leaf can be the first step in tree identification. There are two different leaf types, hardwood and softwood. <br />· Hardwoods can have either a simple or a compound leaf. A simple leaf has a single blade or lamina, as shown in figure 1. A compound leaf has two or more blades that are called leaflets. The stalk to which the blades are attached is called a rachis. The arrangement of the leaflets on the rachis determines the particular type of compound leaf. There are several types of compound leaves.</string>
    <string name="pinnately_compound_leaf">A pinnately compound leaf has leaflets arranged laterally on the rachis.</string>
    <string name="odd_number_of_leafnets">A leaf with an odd number of leaflets on the rachis is called an odd pinnate leaf. A boxelder tree has odd pinnate leaves.</string>
    <string name="even_number_of_leaflets">leaf with an even number of leaflets is called an even pinnate, such as the hornless common honeylocust</string>
    <string name="bippinetary">A bipinnately compound leaf has multiple leaflets attached to a leaf-bearing stalk off the rachis, such as the Kentucky coffeetree.</string>
    <string name="palmatery">A palmately compound leaf has each leaflet attached to a common point, such as the Virginia creeper</string>
    <string name="leaf_types_2">· Softwoods, such as conifers, usually have different leaf types than hardwoods. Not all softwoods have evergreen foliage. The three types of softwood leaves are awl-like, scale-like, and needle-like.</string>
    <string name="awl_like_leaves">Awl-like needles are elongated, taper to a fine point, and are usually sharp to the touch. Many Junipers have awl-like shaped foliage</string>
    <string name="scale_like_foliage">Scale-like foliage overlaps like the shingles on a roof or the scales of a fish. This type of foliage often feels soft when touched. The eastern redcedar has this type of foliage.</string>
    <string name="needle_like_foliage">Needle-like foliage, like that of the pine family, is found on several evergreen genera and species. Needles may be flat or angular in cross-section. The number of needles and the length of the needles may also help in identification.</string>
    <string name="leaf_shape">The shape of the leaf is very useful in tree identification and is usually the same on all trees in a species. Determined by the outline of the blade of the leaf, there are several different shapes, some of which are shown in figure 10. Leaflets on a compound leaf may have two different shapes, depending whether they are located on the side or tip of the stalk.</string>
    <string name="leaf_arrangement">Observing how leaves are arranged on a twig may assist in tree identification. Hardwood leaves are arranged in one of three ways, opposite, whorled and alternate</string>
    <string name="opposite_arrangement">Opposite leaf arrangement refers to leaves that are even with each other on opposite sides of the twig.</string>
    <string name="wroled_arrangement">Three or more leaves found at the same node, or bud, on a twig are whorled.</string>
    <string name="alternate_arrangement">Alternate leaf arrangement occurs when one leaf is attached at each node, arranged in a spiral pattern around the twig.</string>
    <string name="leaf_venation">The venation, or the pattern of the veins, may help in identifying hardwood trees. The four primary venation patterns are pinnate, palmate, parallel, and dichotomous.</string>
    <string name="pinnate_venation">Pinnate venation has a prominent central vein that extends from the base, where the petiole attaches to the blade, to the apex or tip of the leaf. The overall effect is that of a fishbone</string>
    <string name="palmate_venation">Palmate venation is when three or more veins branch from the base of a leaf.</string>
    <string name="parallel_venation">The veins run parallel to each other along the length of the leaf in parallel venation.</string>
    <string name="dichotomous_venation">With dichotomous venation the veins extend for a distance forming a \"Y\" type pattern. It is found in a limited number of leaves.</string>
    <string name="apex_definition">The tip of a blade that is farthest from the petiole, or stalk, is called the apex. The part of the blade nearest to the petiole is called the base.</string>
    <string name="leaf_margin">The edge of the leaf is called the margin. The margin is distinctive and may serve to assist in separating closely related forms.</string>
    <string name="leaf_surface">The surface and texture of the leaf are other means of identification. The hair, resin glands, waxes, blooms, and scales provide valuable clues in naming a tree. The texture of the leaf may feel like leather or like paper.</string>
    <string name="twigs_and_stem">Twigs are useful in identifying trees except for a short period during the spring when the buds are opening and shoots are elongating on these small branches. Several features of twigs, including buds, leaf scars, lenticels, pith, spurs, thorns, spines, and prickles, can help describe them (table 5 and figure 21). Other factors to consider are color, taste, and odor. The color of the bark can be an most important feature on young stems</string>
    <string name="buds_description">· Are one location of growth tissue in a tree. <br />· Are usually visible on the twig. <br />· May be either lateral, on the side of the twig, or terminal, at the tip of the twig. <br />· Are scaly or naked, smooth or fuzzy.</string>
    <string name="leaf_scars_descritption">· Are where a leaf falls from the twig. <br />· Vary in size and shape. <br />· Have one or more minute dots or patches that show where the ruptured strands of vascular tissue passed from twig to leaf.</string>
    <string name="lenticels_description">· Are small, normally lens-shaped patches on the stem that facilitate gas exchange. <br />· May be wart-like.</string>
    <string name="pith_description">· Is the central portion of the twig. <br />· Is usually lighter or darker than the wood that surrounds it. <br />· Varies in color. <br />· Is star-shaped or pentagonal in oaks, triangular in alders, terete or cylindrical-like in ash and elms, and chambered in walnuts. <br />· Varies in composition; in most cases is solid, spongy, or hollow.</string>
    <string name="spurs_description">· Are dwarfed twigs with some internodal development. <br />· May grow for several years. <br />· Produce the fruit on many apple varieties</string>
    <string name="thorns_spines_prickles_description">· Pointed structures that project from the sides of a twig; are important features in some species. · Thorns are modified twigs. · Spines are modified stipules. · Prickles develop from surface tissue and are easily removed.</string>
    <string name="bark_description">Bark is one of the most important features for tree identification because of its year-round accessibility. It is especially useful when the tree’s leaves and twigs are inaccessible or unavailable during the fall and winter. The shape of the bark is characteristic of some species, for example, the small, rectangular plates on flowering dogwood. Bark on young trees differs from that on more mature trees. Experience is the best way to learn bark characteristics.</string>
    <string name="shape_or_general_apperance_description">The shape of the bark is often characteristic of some species, for example, the small-rectangular plates on the flowering dogwood.</string>
    <string name="texture_desciption">The feel of the bark, such as the smoothness of cherry trees or the layering or plating of white oaks, is important</string>
    <string name="thickness_descriptions">The thickness of the bark can vary within a species as well as between species.</string>
    <string name="bark_desctiptions">Bark color varies with age, location, site, and light conditions.</string>
    <string name="flowers_description">Flowers are best feature for identifying trees, but are available only for a short period each year. Leaves, twigs, and bark are usually available for identification, but if there is doubt about a certain tree, the flower is the surest way to identify it. <br />Although not always noticeable to the casual observer, all hardwoods bear flowers. Some produce flowers annually, while others flower less often. Flowers are modified leaves that have undergone change to the point that they have become or support the reproductive organs of the plants.</string>
    <string name="complete_and_incomplete_description">A complete flower has four parts. An incomplete flower is one that lacks any of these four parts. <br />· Calyx (composed of sepals) <br />· Corolla (composed of petals) <br />· Stamens <br />· Pistils</string>
    <string name="perfect_amd_imperfect_description">A perfect flower includes actively functioning organs of both sexes but may lack sepals or petals. The stamen is the male reproductive structure, and the pistil is the female reproductive structure. <br />A perfect flower may be either complete or incomplete. A flower lacking either functional stamens or pistils is imperfect. These flowers may also be known as unisexual flowers, meaning they are either pistilate (female) or staminate (male). These may occur on the same tree, or the male and female parts may be on separate trees, as in the gingko</string>
    <string name="arrangement_of_flower_blooms">Flowers bloom in different arrangements. <br />· Individual or single bloom flowers are typical of many woody plants, for example the magnolia. <br />· A cluster or an inflorescence is a collection of individual flowers arranged in a specific pattern (Dirr 1990). One that blooms at the end of a central stalk, or rachis, is referred to as a determinate flower. The dogwood tree has a determinate flower. If the flowers open progressively from the base to the apex or from the outside to the center in flat-topped clusters, the flower is indeterminate. The flowering crabapple has an indeterminate flower. <br />A flower at the end of a twig is a terminal flower. An inflorescence that appears in a leaf axil, or bud, is described as axillary. Flowers may also appear from separate flower buds, which are normally located near the tips of the twigs.</string>
    <string name="fruit_and_seed_description">Another key to identifying a hardwood is its fruit or seed. A fruit is the seed-bearing organ of the plant. Using fruit is somewhat limited, however, because some trees do not bear fruit and others do so only for a short time or at irregular intervals. Fruits develop from flowers. Solitary flowers that have a single pistil produce a single fruit. A cluster of flowers with multiple pistils produces a cluster of fruit or a compound fruit. Some fruits have only one seed, others develop many seeds. In most species, pollination and fertilization must occur for fruit to develop. Fruit development can take from a week or two in elms to two growing seasons in red oaks.</string>
    <string name="fruit_and_seed_description_2">Seed production and germination depend on many factors, such as temperature extremes, conditions of the tree, and presence or absence of competition. Seed quality, including germination capacity, can vary greatly and is influenced by factors such as the tree’s nutrient storage, availability of water, and temperatures and weather conditions.</string>
    <string name="simple_fruits_description">Simple fruits develop in various forms. There are two basic types, dry and fleshy, each of which has a wide range of variations. <br />· The two primary forms of dry fruit are indehiscent, which do not split open at maturity, and dehiscent, which do split open when ripe. Indehiscent fruits are usually one-seeded with the seed enclosed in various types of coverings. Species with this type of fruit include maples and oaks. Dehiscent fruits are usually many seeded and are enclosed in a covering that splits when the fruit is ripe, such as the redbud, magnolia, and rhododendron. <br/>· Fleshy fruits are usually multi-seeded, the seeds are surrounded by a fleshy pulp, or pericarp, which is sometimes edible. These may be classified as a berry (blueberry and persimmon), drupe (cherry, plum, and holly), or pome (apple or pear).</string>
    <string name="compound_fruit_description">Fruits that develop from multiple pistils are called compound. Two types of compound fruit are aggregrate and multiple. <br />· Aggregate fruits develop from a single flower that has many pistils (Dirr 1990) that form many fruitlets in a single mass, such as the magnolia or tulip tree. <br />· When several flowers together contribute to the development of a single fruit, it is called a multiple fruit (Dirr 1990). The fig tree and the mulberry produce examples of this type of fruit.</string>
    <string name="cones_description">Seeds for softwoods (conifers) are found in cones. Most conifers are monecious. Monecious means that both male and female reproductive parts are located in separate structures on the same tree. A few conifers are dioecious; the male and female reproductive parts are on separate trees. Male and female structures are called cones or stobili. Cones consist of an egg or pollen-bearing scales attached to the central stem. The scales may be arranged spirally or they may appear in pairs.</string>
    <string name="pollen_cones_description">· Are generally small, non-woody and short lasting. <br />· Emerge from buds, release pollen, wither and drop within a few weeks. <br />· Bear sacs on the bottom of each scale known as pollen sacs or microsporangia. <br />· Release thousands of pollen grains when the sacs burst. <br />· Are modifications of shoots, and the scales are modified leaves. <br />· Are found in the mid- to lower crown.</string>
    <string name="female_cones_description">· Are larger than male cones. <br />· Are usually woody. <br />· May persist for many years. <br />· Develop to maturity in one or more season and release their seeds in late summer to autumn. <br />· Bear two megasporangia on the top of each scale which contains an ovule. This ovule develops into a seed following pollination and develops an embryo. <br />· Are found in the upper crown of a tree in some species.</string>
    <string name="seritinous_cone_description">· These cones are closed tightly with pine tar. Heat from a fire is needed to open the cone. The sand pine and pitch pine have this type of cone.</string>
    <string name="tree_form_and_shape_description">Tree form and shape can be useful features for identification. There are two primary tree forms, excurrent and decurrent. Trees that are excurrent, such as conifers, have a dominant trunk with smaller side branches. This form gives the tree a conical or triangular shape. Trees that are decurrent, such as oaks, have spreading branches that give the crown a full, round appearance. <br />A tree may grow differently in various parts of its range so its appearance may vary. A tree that grows large in one part of its range may be shrub-like at the extreme limit of its range.</string>
    <string name="urban_influence_description">Tree identification in urban areas can be complicated. There are usually a large number of species in urban areas, including native and exotic trees. And various conditions associated with the urban environment may alter specific characteristics of a tree, such as changing the appearance of the leaves or bark that help in tree identification. Examples of site factors that may alter a tree’s appearance include compacted soils, excessive soil moisture, and extreme temperatures.</string>
    <string name="size_form_shape_urban_environment">In an urban environment, trees are often growing in very different conditions than those species growing in a rural or forested area. Trees in urban locations are often smaller and shaped differently than those in forests for several reasons.</string>
    <string name="individual_specimen">In urban locations, a tree is often planted as an individual specimen. This exposes it to more light and wind, and usually higher temperatures. Urban trees also will commonly have larger crowns and thicker and shorter trunks than the same species growing in a forest.</string>
    <string name="range_may_change">It is important to remember that a tree’s range may change as the environment is altered. One factor that may change the range is the loss of trees when an area is urbanized. Fewer trees may change the temperature and the flow patterns of wind and water. Another factor that alters the range of a species is its introduction to new areas. When a plant foreign to a region becomes established and reproduces, it is said to be \"naturalized.\" These two situations may greatly extend the range of a tree or reduce it to the point of extinction. Planting a tree out of its natural range can also influence its form and shape. For example, planting river birches far from the river may change their appearance</string>
    <string name="soil_conditions">Soil conditions, such as limited soil volume, compaction, drainage, poor aeration, and limited nutrients can influence sprouting and twig elongation may be shortened.</string>
    <string name="pruning">Pruning can change the natural shape of a tree.</string>
    <string name="leaves_urban_environment">The soil conditions at the site can also influence leaf size and color. <br />· Leaves may be stunted in size. <br />· Color may be altered.</string>
    <string name="bark_urban_influence">The bark of a tree can also be influenced by the urban environment. · In heavily shaded areas lichen may grow on the bark, changing the color. · If the bark has been damaged by insects, rodents, or other pests identification in the winter may be difficult.</string>
    <string name="flowers_urban_influence">Urban locations may affect the natural cycle of a tree’s growth. · Variations in light and temperature patterns may change the time of year that a tree produces new foliage, flowers, or fruits · Soil fertility also influences the time that a tree flowers and the number of flowers produced.</string>
</resources>